ABHISHEK KUMAR

System Engineer Bangalore, India

Mobile: +91-9538401680

Email: abhishek.kumar9214@gmail.com



Professional Summary

2.5 years of experience as UX/UI Web developer with strong technical skills in web application software design, development, analysis, documentation, testing & implementation using various web development tools and technologies. I've also an experience of developing middle-tier applications and Chatbots

Technical Skills			
Web Technologies	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, Twitter BootStrap,JQuery, D3.JS, Node JS, Angular, Angular Js, Express JS, JWT		
Database	MS-SQL Server 2012, MongoDB		
Programming Languages	Typescript, C, C++, Python, Shell Programming		
IDE & Tools	Adobe XD, Visual Studio Code, Postman		
Version Control	GIT		
Methodologies	Agile, Waterfall		
Others tools and technologies	Dialogflow, Google Apps Script, Anypoint Studio, SOAP-UI		

Experience

Tata Consultancy Services (Oct 26, 2015 - Present)

Client description: Worldwide leader in IT and networking

Dec 2017 - Present

Role: UI Developer

- Responsibilities:
 - Developed modular, secure, and well-tested front-end code using Angular 4, ng-bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3 & D3.JS
 - Performed unit testing on various browser for cross browser compatibility and better user experience.
- Environment: Angular 4, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, ng-bootstrap, D3.JS

Role: Chatbot developer

- Responsibilities:
 - Migrated from Paper-Checklist to an interactive Bot Checklist using Cisco Spark Bot, Dialogflow as NLP, Node Js & Express Js to create RESTful APIs
 - Handled various scenarios where Bot couldn't understand user input or couldn't connect to a server
- Environment: Node JS, Express Js, MongoDB, DialogFlow, Nodemailer, Visual Studio Code

Role: MEAN Stack Developer

- Responsibilities:
 - Collaborate with the team members on requirements analysis, creating wireframes, design, configuration, documentation, planning, security and quality assurance
 - Used Node Js and Express Js for web application backend as well as creating RESTful APIs
 - Used GIT as a version control system throughout the development process
- Environment: Node Js, Angular Js, Express Js, MongoDB, JWT, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, jQuery, GIT, Visual Studio Code, Postman

Role: Front-End AngularJS Developer

- Responsibilities:
 - Worked in a team, involved in designing the user experience interface UI/UX strategy and developing the UI
 - Created dynamic web pages where the content was fetched via API calls and updated the DOM
 - o Handled all aspects of the web application including unit testing, debugging and deploying
- Environment: Angular JS, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, Javascript, ¡Query, Visual Studio Code

Role : Mulesoft Developer

- Responsibilities:
 - Developed RESTful/SOAP web services in Mule ESB 3.7.3 based on SOA architecture
 - Involved in Requirements gathering, analysis, design, development and testing phases of Application
- Environment: Anypoint Studio, CloudHub, MULE Runtime Engine 3.7.3, SOAP UI, Postman

TCS ILP Oct 2015 - Jan 2016

Training program of TCS, where I was trained on various aspects of C#, ASP.NET, MS SQL Server 2012, Python, Linux and Unix including hands on and a test post completion of every technology training

Education			
B.E - CSE	SJBIT, Bangalore	67.6%	
Class (10+2), Intermediate	Sree Ayyappa Public School, Bokaro	69.5%	
Class 10, SSC	D.A.V Public School, Dhanbad	89.5%	

Awards & Achievements

- Awarded Employee of the month for the month of October 2017.
- Received On The Spot Award for outstanding ability & skill to represent portrait of legends in minimal time
- Received On The Spot Award for picking up the things in a short period of time on niche skills and successfully implementing them.
- Coordinated and hosted multiple event at the Annual College Technical fest.